<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Authors | The Miller Lab</title>
    <link>/authors/</link>
      <atom:link href="/authors/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Authors</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 13:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/img/MLab_logo_5.png</url>
      <title>Authors</title>
      <link>/authors/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/admin/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2019 13:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/admin/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Michael Miller, MD, PhD, FAAD&lt;/strong&gt; is a Board-Certified Dermatologist and Medical Oncologist at Massachusetts General Hospital and investigator in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.massgeneral.org/cancer-center&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Massachusetts General Hospital Cancer Center&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The Miller Lab&amp;rsquo;s long-term goal is to identify and develop novel therapeutics for advanced skin cancer and to understand the mechanism of response and resistance to those therapies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Miller graduated with Honors from Boston College where he earned a BA in Political Science.  He received his medical (MD) and PhD degree in Biomedical Sciences from the University of Massachusetts.  While at UMass, Dr. Miller received the American Diabetes Association Physician-Scientist Training Award, a Fuller Foundation grant, and he was inducted into the Alpha Omega Honor Society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He then completed a Dermatology residency at Columbia University Medical Center, followed by a residency in Internal Medicine at Brigham and Women&amp;rsquo;s Hospital. Following both residencies, Dr. Miller completed fellowship training in Hematology/Oncology at Beth Israel Deaconess Medical Center and in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.fda.gov/about-fda/scientific-internships-fellowships-trainees-and-non-us-citizens/oncology-center-excellence-fellows-program&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Oncology Center of Excellence&lt;/a&gt; at the Food and Drug Administration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Miller is one of the very few clinicians in the country who is board certified in Internal Medicine, Dermatology and Medical Oncology. He currently practices both Dermatology and Medical Oncology in the Massachusetts General Hospital Cancer Center and at Massachusetts Eye and Ear Infirmary, where he co-directs multidiscliplinary clinics in advanced skin cancer, including the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.massgeneral.org/cancer-center/treatments-and-services/melanoma/merkel-cell-carcinoma&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Merkel Cell Carcinoma Treatment Program&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Miller belongs to several professional organizations, including the American Academy of Dermatology, Medical Dermatology Society, and the American Society of Clinical Oncology.  He has numerous peer-reviewed publications and he has presented his work at the Society for Investigative Dermatology, New York Academy of Medicine, the American Academy of Dermatology, and the U.S. FDA.  He is also a reviewer for the British Journal of Dermatology, Journal of Investigative Dermatology, JAEDV, and Clinical Cancer Research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Due to his expertise in Merkel Cell Carcinoma and Squamous Cell Carcinoma, Dr. Miller has also served on advisory boards to several pharmaceutical companies, inlcuding Pfizer, Merck, Regeneron and Sanofi Genzyme.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Miller Lab&amp;rsquo;s research portfolio consists of clinical and translational projects in &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.merkelcellcarcinoma.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Merkel Cell carcinoma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, cutaneous &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.squamouscellcarcinoma.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Squamous Cell Carcinoma&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/a&gt; and Melanoma.  Dr. Miller has received support for his research from the NIH in the form of a loan repayment award, a Research Grant from the American Skin Association, the Paul Carbone, MD fellowship award from ECOG-ACRIN, and the Mentoring Award in Oncology, Advanced Analytics and Regulatory Science from Project Data Sphere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Board Certifications&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Dermatology, American Board of Dermatology&lt;br /&gt;
Internal Medicine, American Board of Internal Medicine&lt;br /&gt;
Medical Oncology, American Board of Internal Medicine&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.massgeneral.org/doctors/20354/david-miller&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Dr. Miller&amp;rsquo;s Link to the MGH Cancer Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/sophia-shalhout/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/sophia-shalhout/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sophia Shalhout PhD&lt;/strong&gt; joined the Miller Lab as the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.themillerlab.io/post/cutaneous-oncology-research-fellow/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Cutaneous Oncology Research Fellow&lt;/a&gt; in 2019. She obtained her Ph.D. in Chemistry from Wayne State University where she studied the role of activation-induced deaminase (AID) in promoting lymphoma, and developed tools to study and quantify the type of DNA damage caused by aberrant AID  activity. The exploitation of AID-induced DNA damage led to the development of small molecule chemical probes to specifically target lymphoma cells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She then did a postdoctoral fellowship at Boston Children&amp;rsquo;s Hospital in the Camargo lab, where she worked to develop novel small molecule modulators of the Hippo Pathway for applications in both regenerative medicine and chemotherapy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dr. Shalhout is currently using her skills in Biology and Data Science in the Miller Lab  to identify biomarkers of response to therapies for Merkel cell carcinoma.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>/authors/farees-saqlain/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 09:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/farees-saqlain/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Farees Saqlain MSIV&lt;/strong&gt; is a medical student at Harvard Medical School (HMS). Farees is participating in the Scholars in Medicine Program at HMS and conducting his research in the Miller lab. His research is focused on evaluating the natural history of Merkel Cell carcinoma.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Links To Recent Talks By Farees Saqlain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.themillerlab.io/talk/mgh_cutaneous_oncology_tumor_board-12_03_19/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MGH Cutaneous Oncology Tumor Board&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>David M. Miller MD</title>
      <link>/authors/david-m.-miller-md/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/david-m.-miller-md/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAAD</title>
      <link>/authors/faad/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/faad/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PhD</title>
      <link>/authors/phd/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Oct 2019 16:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/phd/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Xin Gao</title>
      <link>/authors/xin-gao/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2017 08:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/authors/xin-gao/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
